The other day my
colleague asked in one
of our internal chats,
guys I have an
Israeli client and he's
asking me is it
safe for me as
an Israeli citizen to
invest in the UAE
because what do you
think about the situation
of 2017 when UAE
had a conflict with
Qatar and at that
point they even closed
the airspace between each
other, all the economic
the economies were actually
on stop between the
two countries. So his
question was very simple,
did UAE take away
the freehold ownership rights
from the Qatari citizens
and that question guide
got me really excited.
I went to Chad
GPT and I started
researching what happened there
now initially I didn't
know because I'm a
citizen of another country
next to a step
government. never came across
this question before. But
what I realize is
that there was the
Arabian Spring in 2011
-12 after which there
were some differences in
the political vision between
the Qatar and the
UAE and in 2017
it evolved into a
conflict where the Qatar
citizens were given briefly
like three weeks to
get out of the
country. Although this was
true and the conflict
lasted till 2021, which
after then it was
fully recovered and citizens
of Qatar were allowed
back, during this time
UAE never took away
the rightful ownership of
those Qatar citizens. This
gave me a little
hint about Dubai. It's
not just how we
we as people who
live here as brokers
see the potential future
of it. It's the
history of Dubai that
tells us that look
at all these questions
on a long run.
Each time the government
is making decisions towards
stability of the economy,
of the citizens and
keeping safety of the
citizens. So they know
even if there is
a conflict here and
now today, in the
future it will be
gone. They will need
to live with it.
So they're taking their
decisions very cautiously, thoughtful.
Long story short. Yeah,
long story short. The
other day, I received
a question from my
colleague in one of
the internal chats. She
has an Israeli client
who's asking, Hey, I'm
a bit scared of
investing in Dubai because
what if they take
away my ownership rights?
What do you think
about the conflict between
Qatar and UAE in
2017? I read the
question. I'm like, what
conflict between Qatar and
UAE? So I went
researching, found out that
there was one. And
it actually lasted till
2021. And even the
citizens of Qatar were
asked to leave the
country of UAE during
this time. But even
during this time, there
weren't any massive cases
of taking away the
property of those people.
So this gives us
an idea of the
position. The strategic thinking
of supreme leaders of
our country. They're always
thinking about the future.
They have a plan
10, 20 years up
ahead.
Probably even more plans
than any other country
I know.
Let's go!
In Ras Al Khaimah.
And there was a
funny story. There were
several people going with
us. And on the
way there, I think
we had a stop
in one of the
gas stations. And his
child, he accidentally spilled
the coffee on the
car. On the car
remote system. And the
car wasn't working at
all. Eventually, we went
to the camping. And
he put his family
with someone in another
car. And when it
was time to leave,
we asked our friends
to take his family
with them. And take
him back home. But
since his car was
stuck in Ras Al
Khaimah, we decided to
stay in the mountains
together. So, it was
a funny situation. That
we were just, you
know, we barely know
each other. But he's
definitely fond of the
nature and stuff. So,
we spent the whole...
night talking about investment,
lifestyle in Dubai. And
then in the morning,
we went to recover
his car. And it
was another funny story
of how we worked
out this whole procedure
with three Pakistani guys
that were trying to
take money from us.
But that really created
a strong bond between.
That was nice. That's
how things happen between
clients and brokers in
my world.
I try to can
a few investor to
do so from two
to be a down
payments, and then I
pay them. You look
like this. And everything's
pretty normal for here,
because they can do
it broke through here,
they can sit back
,pit and let it
Generally people are Tot
Sawyer end up or
similar if it was
for categories for us
to decide where he
was looking forward to
The car was happily,
the car was coming
in a very comfortable
state and feels like
a modern car.